《絕命律師》前情提要
Previously on AMC's "Better Call Saul"...
你剛剛承認犯了一項重罪你知道吧
You do realize you just confessed to a felony?
你就為了這個  毀了我們的家
For this, you destroyed our family?
你現在滿意了嗎
You happy now?!
-吉米  -你打算怎么做
- Jimmy! - What are you gonna do?
他把我困住了
He's got me boxed in.
你可以放手一搏
You can fight this.
我非常懊悔  后悔到你完全無法想象
I regret it all, more than you can imagine,
因為你是我的哥哥
'cause you're my brother.
我會提交對錄音的查禁請求
I'm filing a motion to suppress that tape.
撇開動議  那盤錄音帶會被播放的
Motions aside, that tape will be played.
怎么樣
Well?
猜對了
Bingo.
翻譯     斯嘉麗躺等成績  克里斯  肉松
翻譯     十月   joy_bwl   Eunice  吃冰棒
校對     喃喃  克里斯
時間軸     念念 今 壬虛浪影
后期      蠟筆小新的眉毛
總監      喃喃
找到一部電話
Found a phone!
看起來像六十年代的東西  但應該能用
It looks like it's from 1967, but I think it'll work.
稍等  吉米
Just a sec, Jimmy.
真好  謝謝你這么小心
Excellent. Thank you for being so careful.
先生
Sir.
-我們得進你的閣樓  -為什么
- We have to get in your attic. - For what?
接線
Oh, the hook-up.
不  沒關系的  不用了
Oh, no. That's all right. Don't bother.
不到二十分鐘就能弄好
Oh, it won't take 20 minutes.
要是不裝的話  你用不了
Plus, you really can't use it if I don't do it.
不  沒事  我們不會用的
No, it's all right. We're not gonna.
你這邊弄好以后
Uh, when you're done here,
能不能在車庫里多裝幾盞燈
would you get some more lamps in the garage?
謝謝
Thanks. ‭
-我們找到了一部電話  -對
- So, we got a phone. - Yeah.
院子里的草割好了
The yard's half-mowed.
插座什么的都沒問題了
Uh, the sockets and stuff are looking a-ok.
我再檢查一遍  確認一下
I'm gonna check again just to make sure.
都快完成了
We're almost there.
好  好
Good. Good.
你覺得呢
Um, what do you think?
戴上還是摘下來
On? Off?
摘下來吧
I think...off.
你說得對  那就摘了
Yeah. You're right. Off it is.
查克
Chuck.
你確定這么做對嗎
You sure this is the right play?
根據我的經驗
I mean, in my experience,
謊言越大  被發現的代價就越大
the bigger the lie, ‭the harder it can be to dig out.
船到橋頭自然直
I'll cross that bridge when I come to it.
原創翻譯  雙語字幕
最新連載海外影視劇下載
請登陸 www.YYeTs.com
僅供交流學習  禁止商用盈利
伙計們  燈裝好了
‭Hey, guys, think we're set with the lamps.
能幫我弄一下這部電話嗎  謝謝
Uh, could someone give me a hand with this phone? Gracias.
門開著呢
It's open!
麗貝卡
Rebecca.
-查克  -你看起來真漂亮
- Chuck. - You look lovely.
-見到你真高興  -我也是
- Oh, it's so good to see you. - And you.
點蠟燭干什么
Hey, what's with the candles?
你為什么不摸黑坐著
Why you sittin' here in the dark?
我也奇怪呢
Ye, I was wondering the same thing.
天啊  今天這一下午啊
Oh, my God, the afternoon I've had.
兩小時前  我把鱸魚拿出來
Two hours ago, I take the sea bass out.
我剛把它收拾好放在那兒
No sooner is it prepped and resting
結果突然就停電了
than -- boom! -- power goes down.
我給市里打過電話了
I get on the phone to the city.
長話短說
To make a long story short,
那幫公共服務公司的傻瓜弄混了我的電費
those bozos at PNM mixed up my payment.
圣克里斯托瓦爾路512號那個賴賬的
The deadbeat at 512 San Cristobal
還沒還錢
hasn't been paying his bills.
當然  我是...
And, of course, I'm...
-215號  -沒錯  215
- 215. - 215, exactly.
他們說明天之前會來電
They say they'll have it on again by tomorrow.
與此同時  我向鄰居借了些野營裝備
In the meantime, I borrowed some camping gear from my neighbors.
所以才弄得這么鄉野氣息
Hence, the rustic flair.
-天啊  -是啊
- Jeez. - Oh, yeah.
那我們怎么辦
So, what do we do?
出門下館子嗎
Uh, get out of here and go to a restaurant?
我們去吃四季餐廳吧  你請客
We could hit Seasons. Your treat.
這樣也行
We could, yeah.
但晚飯快做好了
But, um, you know, dinner's almost ready.
還有魚  不吃的話只能把它扔了
And the fish -- I would have just had to throw it out.
我只需要把它放進鍋里就行了
All I have to do is toss it in a pan.
要不我們湊合一下算了
How about we just rough it?
你們同意嗎
You okay with that?
為什么不呢  會很有意思的
Well...why not? It'll be fun.
我們可以來一次高級料理露營
We'll do an haute-cuisine camp-out.
太好了  那就這么定了  我幫你拿外套吧
Great! Then it's settled. Let me take that.
-脫掉外套  -好  給
- Take your... - Oh, yeah, here.
-包我拿著  -謝謝
- Here, I'll take that. - Oh, thank you.
天啊
Oh, my God.
我一口都吃不下了
I can't eat another bite.
為美食家干杯
Cheers to the Galloping Gourmet.
好
Yeah. ‭
蘋果白蘭地太好喝了
The Calvados is perfect.
你一直都喜歡的
You always liked it.
來吧
Here.
我來吧
Let me get this.
不  吉米  不用麻煩你
No, no, Jimmy. You don't have to.
不  至少讓我洗碗吧
No, least I can do is the dishes.
謝謝
Thank you.
謝謝  吉米
Thanks, Jimmy.
竟然比我預想的好
This turned out better than I thought.
停電的事我很抱歉
Uh, I'm so...sorry about the lights.
挺好的  有氣氛
Oh, it's nice. Atmospheric.
吉米當律師這件事我一直沒法釋懷
I mean, I still can't get over Jimmy being a lawyer.
我也是
Neither can I.
他能獨當一面了
He's got his own shingle out and everything.
他能做一名真正的負責的公民
I mean, a real, responsible citizen.
誰能想到這一天呢
I mean, who woulda thought?
是啊
Yeah.
這地方也一樣
This place is the same.
我本來想到你會
I mean, I-I would've thought you'd
換新家具
change things up.
挪動擺設
Move things around.
你品味非常棒  要是還沒壞掉的話
You've got great taste. And if it ain't broke...
巡演怎么樣
How's the tour going?
很好  很不錯
It's good. Good.
今年秋天去遠東
Um, the Far East this fall.
中國  韓國  越南
Uh, China, South Korea, and Vietnam.
-那肯定很讓人興奮  -是啊
- That's gonna be exciting. - Yeah.
這周去過圣達菲之后
And then, um, after Santa Fe this week,
我們回中歐
uh, we're back to Central Europe.
好玩嗎
And it's good?
-有很多酒店  -是啊
- Well, it's a lot of hotels. - Yeah.
在布達佩斯  我看到的大多是
I mean, in Budapest, I think I saw mostly
歌劇廳內部和萬豪酒店
the inside of the concert hall and the Marriott.
但我不該抱怨
But, you know, I shouldn't complain.
你這不是抱怨  是在觀察
You're not complaining. You're observing.
你終于見到薩爾茨堡了嗎
Did you finally get to see Salzburg?
還沒  等下個月去完維也納之后
Not yet, but next month, after Vienna.
你還記得當時我們想去薩爾茨堡嗎
Do you remember when we tried to go to Salzburg?
那個騎著小摩托車的瘋老太婆
And that crazy old lady on the scooter...
-記得  記得  -把我們攆出火車站
- Oh, yes! Yes! - ‭...chased us out of the train station.
是啊
Yeah!
然后我們在因斯布呂克
And then, um -- ‭And then we went and got, uh,
吃到了樹莓林茨蛋糕
it was a-a-a raspberry Linzer torte in Innsbruck?
為了讓我們心情好起來
‭To make ourselves feel better?
你說"我們肯定吃不完這么多"
You said, "We'll never finish this!"
結果我們吃完了
And then we did.
那去過亞洲之后呢  要在國內旅游嗎
So, what's after Asia? Any plans for a stateside tour?
希望明年能有機會
Oh, you know, hopefully next year.
也許會買個房子  那就太好了
You know, maybe a residency. Oh, that would be sweet.
我喜歡長途大巴
I mean, you know, I like the buses
火車和飛機  但我...
and trains and planes fine, but I, um...
我真懷念有家的日子  能有個地方掛帽子
I miss having one -- one place to hang my hat.
天啊
Oh, God!
抱歉  我討厭那玩意
I'm sorry. I-I-I hate that thing.
感覺自己被拴著
I feel like I'm on a leash.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
是我的指揮
It's my conductor.
這個電話我必須接  抱歉
Um, I have to take this. I'm sorry.
你好  安德烈
H-hi, Andre.
不  我在吃飯  怎么了
No, I'm just at dinner. What's up?
我排練時可以試試看
Well, I can do that at rehearsal.
沒問題
Yeah, no problem. Yeah.
不  我知道他們在第16小節反應慢了
No, I-I know that they're coming in late on bar 16.
對  知道了
Y-Yeah. Got it. Got it.
我會確保...
I will make sure that --
你能等一下嗎
Uh, c-c-can you hold on a second?
我去拿根筆
Let me just get a pen.
對  不...
Yeah. No, I-I...
對  等我一下
Yeah, hold on one second.
對  沒問題  你說了算
Yeah, I can do it -- I mean, whatever you need.
好的
Mm-hmm. Okay.
好了  說吧
All right, shoot.
好
Okay...
查克
Chuck?
我沒事
I'm all right.
你希望我把大提琴部分單獨排練嗎
Well, do you want me to rehearse the cellists separately?
麗貝卡  麗貝卡
Rebecca. Rebecca.
不  不只是他  整個樂隊都有問題
Well, no, it's not just him. It's the whole section.
麗貝卡
Rebecca!
不
Uh, no.
沒關系
T-That's fine.
對
Yeah.
查克  搞什么
Chuck, what the hell?!
安德烈
Andre?
我得等會打給你了
I-I-I have to -- I'll have to call you back.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
你什么毛病
What is your problem?
說話啊
Say something.
不顧一起就餐的人
It is incredibly bad manners
去接電話  這樣太無禮了
to answer a cellphone in company.
太粗魯了
It's very rude.
對不起
Uh, I-I'm sorry.
我不知道你會這么想
I-I didn't know that you felt that way.
我沒想冒犯你  查克
I...didn't mean to offend you, Chuck.
我可能反應過激了
I-I may have overreacted.
我太唐突了
That was very abrupt.
不
No.
我明白
I understand.
不早了
It's getting late.
謝謝你的款待
Thank you for a lovely dinner,
但我該回酒店了
but I should be getting back to the hotel.
等我一下  我們...
Just gimme a minute, and we can --
不  我打車就行了
No. Uh, um, I'll just get a cab.
-我不想再麻煩你們了  -讓我去吧
- I don't want to put you out any more. - Please, let me.
真不用了
No, really.
我打車就行
A cab is the easiest.
你得做點什么
You gotta do somethin'.
你不能讓她這樣走掉
Y-You can't let her leave like this.
告訴她是怎么回事
Just tell her what's going on.
不  不
No. No.
她會理解的
She'll understand.
你寧可讓她覺得你是個暴躁的混蛋
She'll -- Would you rather she think you're a raging prick
也不愿說出真相嗎
than know the truth?
不
No.
如果你不說  我去告訴她
Look, if you won't tell her, then I will.
不不不
No, no. No!
你不許告訴她
You will not tell her.
You...will not tell her.
好吧
All right.
安德烈  真抱歉
Hi, Andre. Yes, I'm sorry about that.
我把手機弄掉了
I dropped the phone.
絕命律師
第三季  第五集
天啊  你在搞什么  伙計
Jesus. What're you doing, man?
袋子里都快沒氧氣了
There's barely any oxygen in that bag.
-你快把她悶死了  -"她"
- You're suffocating her! - "Her"?
對  你沒看到漂浮著的小丁丁
Yeah, just because ‭you don't see swingin' dicks
不代表你就分不清它的性別
doesn't mean you can't tell a boy fish from a girl fish.
明白了
Oh, yeah, see.
我看到它的口紅了
Now I can see the lipstick.
這是一條生命  不是一件家具
This is a living creature. It's not a piece of furniture.
我們會面結束后  你帶她回去
So, after this, you take her home.
把她放到一個大魚缸里  至少一加侖那種
You put her in a big bowl, at least a gallon.
弄個好的換氣閥  再放條清道夫
‭Get a good bubbler, maybe a plecostomus.
別喂她太多了
And don't feed her too much.
人會變胖
People get fat.
魚會淹死在吃剩的食物里
Fish, they drown in leftover food.
好了好了  海洋學家
All right already, Jacques Cousteau.
我懂了
Point made.
那就好
Good.
我猜我們那位朋友讓你來找我
I'm guessing our friend didn't refer you to me
不是為了養魚建議吧
to get ichthyological advice.
我要找個能靈活處事的人
I'm looking for someone with a light touch.
我說的不是那種在連鎖超市
I'm not talking some teenager taking a five-finger discount
偷塊奶酪的毛頭小子
on string cheese at the Stop 'N' Shop.
我需要專業  高端  嚴謹的人選
I need highly skilled, high-end, discreet.
真正的專家
A real pro.
你會把他也放在狹小的空間里嗎
You gotta fit him in a tight space?
應該不會
I don't think so.
那我認識你要找的人
I got just the guy, then.
所以我說打高爾夫能廣結人脈
That's why I say golfing is a contact sport.
干得好  韋克斯勒小姐  真是鼓舞人心
Great job, Ms. Wexler. Very refreshing.
相信我  我們很高興這案子沒上庭審
Believe me, uh, we're happy to get this one off the docket.
那也沒我們高興
Not as happy as we are.
干得漂亮
Again, great job.
謝謝  謝謝你  先生
Thank you. Thank you, sir.
女士們  晚飯我請客
Ladies, dinner's on me.
金  我們知道你很棒  但不知道你這么棒
Kim, I knew you were good, but I didn't know you were this good.
我很高興你們滿意
Oh, I'm glad you're happy.
沒有你我們不可能成功
We couldn't have done it without you.
希望你明白
And I hope you realize
這表示以后有好多活兒等著你呢
this means a whole lot a work comin' your way.
那太棒了
Oh, that's -- that's great.
聽上去可不像太棒了
Well, you don't sound like it's great.
我不想掃興
I hate to be a buzzkill,
但我們進一步合作前  有件事
but there is something you need to hear
我得告訴你們
before we get any deeper in.
關于你們的前任律師  查爾斯·麥吉爾
It's about your former attorney, Charles McGill.
他怎么了
What about him?
查爾斯對他弟弟吉米
Charles has been making
提出了一些非常嚴重的指控
some very ugly allegations about his brother, Jimmy,
而我碰巧和吉米同一間辦公室
with whom I happen to share an office space.
指控  關于什么的
Allegations? Of what?
查爾斯認為吉米
Charles thinks that Jimmy
趁他在家整理文件時
somehow took control of your documents
搞到了你們的文件
while he was working on them at his home.
他覺得吉米對數字進行了移位
He believes Jimmy transposed the address numbers.
把數字移位
Transposed the numbers?
他怎么可能做到
How would he even do that?
查爾斯聲稱吉米拿走了
Charles contends that Jimmy took the documents
與羅塞拉分行相關的文件
pertaining to the Rosella branch
趁自己身體欠佳時
and, while Charles was indisposed,
復印并篡改了它們
photocopied and doctored them.
這太異想天開了
That's pretty baroque.
重要的是
The important thing here
我覺得這件事可能會引起輿論關注
is I think it could make some noise in public.
很快
Soon.
我想毫無隱瞞地把這件事告訴你們
I wanted to tell you this in the spirit of full disclosure.
你們還是從我這知道比較好
I thought it was better if you heard it from me.
如果你們有任何顧慮
If you have any reservations at this point
或者對于與我合作感覺不自在
or if you are not comfortable staying with me,
我們可以討論接下來怎么做
we can discuss options.
要說有什么是我不能容忍的
If there's one thing I cannot abide,
就是一個人不能承擔自己的過錯
it's a man who won't own up to his mistakes.
不管麥吉爾在搞什么名堂  都不會
Now, whatever mud McGill is slinging he's not gonna
讓我放棄我見過的最棒的律師
screw me out of the best outside counsel I've ever had.
這...
That's...
我太高興了
I'm so glad to hear that.
我們很感謝你提醒我們
We appreciate the heads-up,
但你可以不用擔心這件事了
but you can call this baby put to bed.
說回正題  晚餐
Now the most important thing -- dinner.
七點行嗎
7:00 good for you?
-我沒問題  -好極了
- Uh, works for me. - Great.
我們商量下接下來的戰略
We'll talk strategy --
是先在科羅拉多州還是先在猶他州
We move on Colorado or Utah first?
七點見
See ya at 7:00.
麥吉爾的事
This McGill thing.
你確定沒問題嗎
You're sure it's not gonna be a problem?
確定
I am.
絕對不會牽扯到梅薩維德
Mesa Verde isn't involved in any way, shape, or form.
那就好
Okay. Good.
那么晚上見了
Then, I'll see you tonight.
好的  晚上見
Okay, great. See you then.
出口
好了  就是這樣
Okay, this is it.
我們可以關掉所有燈光和麥克風
We can run without lights and mics.
在你作證期間
We'll collect all cellphones
將手機統一收集并保存
and hold them for the duration of your testimony.
可以讓法庭書記官
The, uh, court reporter, would it be possible
待在離證人席遠一點的地方嗎
to move him or her farther from the witness stand?
可以  我們可以
Um, yeah, ‭I think we can arrange
把他們安排在法庭后部
having them ‭in the back of the court.
抱歉  這個出口標志的燈光只能保留
I'm sorry. There's nothing I can do about the exit signs.
這是規定
It's code.
感謝你所做的一切
I appreciate all you're doing.
謝謝
Thank you.
阿利先生  可以讓我們單獨待一會嗎
Mr. Alley, I wonder if you'd give us a moment.
我想跟我的同事商量些事情
I'd like to go over something with my colleague.
沒問題  我在外面等你們
No problem. I'll be outside when you're ready.
霍華德
Howard?
你感覺怎么樣  查克
How you feeling, Chuck?
我可以應付過去的
I'll muddle through.
因為要問很多問題
Because this is a lot to ask.
如果你堅持不下來
And if you're not up to it -- just throwing this out there --
那就不如不來作證了
maybe you don't need to testify at all.
不  我要來
No, I do.
我是唯一一個能解釋清楚
I'm the only person who can adequately explain
那盤磁帶是怎么回事的人
the context of that tape.
否則  辯方會歪曲事實的
Otherwise, the defense'll tear it to shreds.
這個案子已經板上釘釘了
It's already a solid case.
我們有吉米訴前轉移的陳述
We have Jimmy's statement from the Pre-Prosecution Diversion.
有我和私家偵探的證詞
There's my testimony and the private eye's.
也許你不必親自到這來遭這份罪
Maybe there's no need to put you through the wringer like this.
重點不是我或者我的身體健康
This isn't about me or my health.
重點在于公關
This is about PR.
我們失去了一個委托人
We lost a client.
原因在于  你失去行動能力
That happened because, while you were...incapacitated,
使你弟弟獲取了
your brother accessed documents
本應保存在律所的文件
that should have been secured at HHM.
吉米的所作所為確實很過分
What Jimmy did ‭is unconscionable, yes...
但我的工作之一是維護公司的聲譽
but one of my jobs is to safeguard the firm's reputation.
現在不是擔心聲譽的時候
This is not the time to worry about how we look.
我們面對的是大是大非的問題
This is about what's right and what's wrong.
我不想讓吉米
I'm not gonna risk Jimmy getting, what?
只是被禁止執業一年  或者兩年
A year's suspension? Maybe two?
他應該被取消律師資格  而不是略受懲戒
He deserves disbarment, not some slap on the wrist.
不  霍華德  只有這一條路可選
No, Howard. ‭There's only one way forward.
縱使天塌下來  該算的賬也要算
Let justice be done, though the heavens fall.
抱歉久等了  安排得非常好
Sorry to keep you waiting. This'll do nicely.
請向委員會轉達我的謝意
Please extend my thanks to the Committee for their flexibility.
早上好  我是州律師協會的羅伯特·阿利
Good morning. I'm Robert Alley for the State Bar.
就詹姆斯·M·麥吉爾先生一案
In the matter of James M. McGill,
州律師協會擬證明其違反以下
the State Bar intends to prove the following violations
道德守則
of the Ethical Code.
16條102款
16-102 --
從事律師所知是犯罪的行為
engaging in conduct a lawyer knows is criminal.
麥吉爾先生明知損壞其兄長家的大門
Mr. McGill certainly knew that breaking down his brother's door
是犯罪行為
was criminal behavior.
16條804款
16-804 --
作為律師  其犯罪行為
committing a criminal act that reflects adversely
對律師的誠實守信產生了不利影響
on the lawyer's honesty or trustworthiness as a lawyer.
任何理性的人都會同意
Any reasonable person would agree
在另一位律師的家中對其進行攻擊
that assaulting another lawyer in his own home
對麥吉爾先生的律師身份產生了惡劣影響
reflects badly on Mr. McGill's fitness as an attorney.
16條304款
16-304 --
非法修改  毀壞
unlawfully altering, destroying,
或隱藏具有潛在證據價值的材料
or concealing material having potential evidentiary value.
麥吉爾先生闖進其兄長家中
Mr. McGill broke into his brother's home
毀壞了一盤盒式錄音磁帶
and destroyed an audiocassette
其中包含一段他和他哥哥
which contained a recording of a conversation
查爾斯·麥吉爾  之間的對話錄音
between himself and his brother, Charles McGill.
我們將說明  這段錄音
We will show that this recording was evidence
是一件進行中案件的證據
in an ongoing legal case.
州律師協會認為
The State Bar believes that,
一旦我們展示了事實
once we have presented the facts,
委員會將會同意
the Committee will agree that disbarment
取消詹姆斯·麥吉爾的律師資格
is warranted for James McGill.
謝謝
Thank you very much.
謝謝  阿利先生
Thank you, Mr. Alley.
韋克斯勒女士
Ms. Wexler?
謝謝  主席先生
Thank you, Mr. Chairman.
早上好
Good morning.
我是金·韋克斯勒  詹姆斯·麥吉爾的協理辯護律師
I'm Kim Wexler, co-counsel with James McGill, for the defense.
各位都已經閱讀了麥吉爾先生的訴前轉移陳述
You've already read Mr. McGill's Pre-Prosecution Statement.
對于非法闖入他哥哥家里這點我們并無疑義
We don't dispute he broke into his brother's house,
而他也對此深感后悔
an act he regrets...deeply.
但這個故事還有另外一面
But there is another side to this story.
無關算計
One not about calculation
及居心不良
or ill intent,
是關于兩兄弟
but about two brothers,
他們的關系  經過數年糾葛
whose relationship, after years of strain,
最終破裂
finally broke.
我們相信  了解事情全部真相后
We believe that, after you have the complete picture,
各位就會明白  詹姆斯·麥吉爾
you'll understand James McGill is an asset
是法律界不可或缺的一員
to our legal community.
他應該保持協會正式成員的身份
And he should remain a full member of it in good standing.
謝謝
Thank you.
謝謝  韋克斯勒女士
Thank you, Ms. Wexler.
好了  如果各位都準備好了...
Okay, if, uh, everyone's ready to begin testimony...
阿利先生  傳喚你的證人
Mr. Alley, call your witness.
砰  砰  砰
Bang! Bang! Bang!
然后他就踢破了大門
Then he kicked down the door.
吉米很激動  不停地大喊大叫
Jimmy was very agitated. He was shouting.
他要求查爾斯
He demanded Charles turn over
-把他收集的證據交出來  -反對
- the evidence he'd been collecting -- - Objection.
我們還沒有確認磁帶是證物
We haven't established the tape is evidence of anything.
辯方只承認它是一項財產
The defense has only acknowledged it as a piece of property.
請讓我重新表述
Allow me to rephrase.
吉米要求查爾斯交出屬于他的一盤磁帶
Jimmy demanded an audiocassette in Charles' possession,
接著
which Jimmy proceeded,
他用一根撥火棍
with the help of an iron fireplace implement,
撬開了查爾斯的書桌
to pry from Charles' desk.
然后  他便將磁帶毀掉了
He then broke the cassette into pieces
轉而與他哥哥對峙
and went on to confront his brother.
被告毀壞磁帶后發生了什么
What happened after the defendant smashed this tape?
布賴特比爾先生和我
Mr. Brightbill and I --
那是查爾斯雇的私家偵探嗎
That's the private investigator that Charles hired?
是的
That's correct.
我們認為吉米可能會襲擊他哥哥
He and I were concerned that Jimmy might strike his brother.
所有我們介入了
So that's when we stepped in.
-謝謝  哈姆林先生  -不客氣
- Thank you, Mr. Hamlin. ‭Certainly.
我沒有問題了
Nothing further at this time.
韋克斯勒女士
Ms. Wexler?
謝謝  主席先生
Thank you, Mr. Chairman.
你說你認識我的當事人一段時間了
You testified you've known my client for some time.
具體是多久
How long exactly?
快十年了
Nearly 10 years.
你是怎么認識他的
How did you come to know him?
他哥哥讓我雇他在公司收發室工作
His brother asked to hire him in the mailroom at our firm.
-然后你就雇了  -是的
- And you did. ‭- Yes.
你當時認為他是個什么樣的人
What was your opinion of him then?
我認為
I thought
他是個很積極的人
he had a lot of get-up-and-go.
工作非常努力
He was a hard worker.
你還給他取了個外號  是嗎
You had a nickname for him, didn't you?
"騙子查理"
"Charlie Hustle."
當你發現他成了律師時感覺如何
How'd you feel when you found out he'd become a lawyer?
驚訝
Surprised.
他自己從法律學校畢業
He'd put himself through law school
通過律師資格考試  沒告訴任何合伙人
and taken the Bar exam without telling any of the partners.
甚至是查爾斯
Even Charles.
他在你的收發室工作
He bootstrapped his way into a law degree
還單打獨斗拿了法學學位
while working in your mailroom.
你們有想過把他雇為律師嗎
Did you consider taking him on as an associate?
有的
We did.
但時間不長
Briefly.
你們似乎沒有雇傭他  為什么
Sounds like you didn't hire him. Why not?
他可是那么努力
With that kind of grit.
合伙人覺得最好
The partners decided it would be best
避免裙帶關系的出現
to avoid the appearance of nepotism.
我們認為雇傭吉米可能有損風紀
We felt hiring Jimmy might damage morale.
裙帶關系
Nepotism.
你們是叫"哈姆林麥吉爾聯合律所"  對吧
Your firm is "Hamlin, Hamlin, and McGill," Right?
另一位哈姆林是誰
Who's the other Hamlin?
我父親
My father.
哪位合伙人最擔心裙帶關系
Which partner was the most concerned with nepotism?
查爾斯·麥吉爾
Charles McGill.
所以是吉米的親兄長將他拒之門外
So Jimmy's own brother blocked him.
反對
Objection.
哈姆林麥吉爾聯合律所的雇傭辦法
How are the hiring practices of Hamlin, Hamlin, McGill
跟此案有何關聯
relevant here?
有助于理解他們兄弟間的關系
It's relevant to understand the relationship between these brothers.
你可以問  韋克斯勒女士
We'll, uh, give you some leeway, Ms. Wexler,
但也別偏離太多
but don't stray too far.
查爾斯·麥吉爾不是本場聽證會的主角
Charles McGill is not the subject of this hearing.
謝謝
Thank you.
吉米知道他兄長正是
Did Jimmy know his brother was the one
阻止你們雇傭他的人嗎
that prevented you from hiring him?
他不知道
No. He did not.
他最后進了戴維斯梅因律所
Eventually, he was hired by the firm of Davis & Main.
我很樂意多提一句  如果你想
I'd be happy to say more about that, if you'd like.
不  謝謝
No. Thank you.
查爾斯出狀況后
When Charles' condition appeared,
吉米在照顧他  對嗎
Jimmy took care of him, didn't he?
是的
I believe so.
吉米在想方設法建立自己的律師業務
Jimmy was struggling to build his solo law practice,
不過他一直雷打不動地
and yet, every single day, without fail,
給他兄長帶食物  生活用品
he brought his brother food, supplies --
甚至是他最愛的報紙  是嗎
even his favorite newspapers. Isn't that right?
是的
He did.
你能談談查爾斯的休假條款嗎
Could you speak to the terms of Charles' leave of absence?
你知道我不能
You know I can't.
是家庭和醫療假  詳情都是機密
It was an FMLA leave. Anything more is confidential.
但你能確定是精神疾病  對吧
But you can confirm it was due to mental illness, correct?
反對  查爾斯·麥吉爾的精神健康不在討論范疇
Objection! Charles McGill's mental health isn't at issue.
這是對律師協會下位證人的抹黑
This is a smear job on the State Bar's upcoming witness --
僅此而已
nothing more.
這不是資格聽證會  韋克斯勒女士
This is not a competency hearing, Ms. Wexler.
哈姆林先生不是精神病專家
Mr. Hamlin is not a psychiatric professional.
你有更多與他經歷
Do you have any questions that would be more germane
更相關的問題嗎
to his experience?
沒了
No.
我沒有更多問題了
I have nothing further.
請證人離席
The witness is excused.
現在  律師協會
At this time, the State Bar would like
想展示五號證物
to enter Exhibit Five into evidence.
我們要求播放查爾斯·麥吉爾的錄音
We ask that Charles McGill's recording be played.
恕我重申我的反對意見
I'm respectfully renewing my objection.
播放這一證物的證明價值
The probative value of playing this Exhibit
不及這一證物的有害影響
is outweighed ‭by how prejudicial it is.
恕我直言  韋克斯勒女士
All due respect to Ms. Wexler,
律師協會認為這對聽證很重要
but the State Bar feels this is fundamental to hear.
我們不希望留下
We don't want to leave any question
對雙方意圖的疑問
as to the intentions of both parties.
韋克斯勒女士  我們在駁回你查禁證據的動議時
Ms. Wexler, we already ruled this was fair game
就已經裁定這是公平的
when we denied your motion to suppress.
另外  你委托人的胡作非為撇開不談
I'll add, the rough-and-tumble of your client's conduct aside,
我們得知道一名律師
we need to know whether one lawyer
是否嘗試篡改另一名律師的證據
attempted to tamper with another's evidence.
來
Come here.
你還在這里做什么
‭‭What are you still doing here?
航班延誤了
Flight's delayed.
延誤了多久
How delayed?
我剛查是四十分鐘
40 minutes, last I checked.
靠  通知我進展
Shit. Okay. Keep me posted.
行
Yes.
好了
Here we go.
謝謝你們耐心等待
Thank you for your patience.
律師協會準備好了
The State Bar is ready to proceed.
抱歉
Um, begging your pardon.
被告要求復核  行嗎
Um, the defense requests a moment to review, if we could?
行
All right.
等你們準備好
When you're ready.
謝謝  主席先生
Thank you, Mr. Chairman.
這是干什么
What are we doing?
我們在拖
We're stalling.
沒錯  沒錯
Yes. Yes.
我弟弟有許多令人欣賞的品質
My brother has many admirable qualities.
從某種程度上來說  我挺欣賞他
I-In some ways, I can say I admire him.
太冷漠了
Too cold.
我愛我弟弟
I love my brother.
但泰德·卡辛斯基[恐怖分子]的兄弟也愛他
But Ted Kaczynski's brother loved him, too.
他也想幫忙
And he wanted to help.
太道貌岸然了
That's sanctimonious.
我愛我弟弟
I love my brother.
他是個好人  他有好的一面
He's a good person. He has good in him.
但法律太重要了
But the law is too important.
馬上到  霍華德
Be right there, Howard!
法律太重要了
The law is too important.
不然我怎么可能說出來
I sure as shit wouldn't be tellin' ya otherwise.
但沒錯  這就是真相
But, yes... it's the truth.
你這么大費周章就為了羞辱我嗎
You'd go to such lengths to humiliate me?
我是為了金
I did it for Kim!
她廢寢忘食拿下梅薩維德銀行
She worked her butt off to get Mesa Verde
而你和霍華德就喝喝威士忌坐享其成
while you and Howard sat around sipping scotch and chortling.
什么哈姆林麥吉爾聯合律所
Hamlin, Hamlin, McGill --
應該叫吝嗇鬼律所才對
more like Scrooge and Marley!
梅薩維德銀行是金的
Kim deserves Mesa Verde --
不是你  也不是哈姆林麥吉爾聯合律所的
not you, not HHM.
她爭取來的  她需要它
She earned it, and she needs it!
我這么做是為了幫她
I did it to help her,
但我真不知道這會給你帶來那么大的傷害
but I-I honestly didn't think it would hurt you so bad.
我以為你只會說  "靠  我犯了個錯誤"
I thought you'd just say, "Oh, crap, I made a mistake,"
然后繼續過你的日子  這才是正常人會干的
and go on with your life, like a normal person!
可你偏不
But, oh, no!
是我太天真
Wishful thinking!
所以  我能不能告訴霍華德
So, can I, uh, tell Howard
你不辭職也不退休了
you're not quitting or retiring or whatever?
還有  能不能把這些破玩意從墻上弄下來
And can we take all this shit down off the walls?
我這就打電話給霍華德
I'm gonna go call Howard.
吉米
Jimmy.
你剛剛承認犯了一項重罪你知道吧
You do realize ‭you just confessed to a felony?
算是吧
I guess.
可你覺得好多了  是吧
But you feel better, right?
再說了  就我們倆  空口無憑
Besides, ‭it's your word against mine.
好了  阿利先生
All right, uh, Mr. Alley, uh,
我們得為下一位證人安排一下
we need to make accommodations for your next witness.
對嗎
Is that correct?
-是  主席先生  -行
- Yes, Mr. Chairman. - All right.
告訴大家  我們得準備一下房間
For those who don't know, we need to prepare the room.
員工會收好你們的手機
Uh, the clerk is going to collect your, uh, cellphones,
手表  密鑰卡  一切電子設備
watches, key fobs -- anything electrical.
如果你們不想這么做
If you prefer not to,
請把東西放到房間之外保管好  謝謝
please secure your items outside this room. Thank you.
謝謝你們的理解
Thank you for understanding.
你的手機  先生
Your phone, sir?
我留在車里了
I left it in the car.
-不好意思  -抱歉
- Oh. Excuse me. - Sorry.
-那是你的  -謝謝
- That's yours. - Thanks.
請舉起你的右手
Please raise your right hand.
你發誓或確認道出事實  沒有隱瞞
Do you swear or affirm to tell the truth, the whole truth,
只說事實嗎
and nothing but the truth?
是的
I do.
你能說出你的姓名嗎
Could you state your name?
查爾斯·L·麥吉爾
Charles L. McGill.
我是哈姆林麥吉爾聯合律所的高級合伙人
I'm a senior partner at the law firm of Hamlin, Hamlin, McGill.
法院書記官能聽得見嗎
Can the court reporter hear me?
聽得見  先生  我能聽清楚
Yes, sir. I can hear you fine.
麥吉爾先生  我盡量簡短一點
Mr. McGill, I'll try to be brief.
我們不必詳述入室行竊
We don't need to dwell on the burglary
或是你遭受侵襲的過程
or the assault that you suffered.
謝謝  我很感激
Thank you. I appreciate that.
我想知道關于這盤磁帶的事
What I would like to hear about is this tape.
什么迫使你錄下了這盤磁帶
What compelled you to make it?
我懷疑我弟弟篡改了我當時經手的
I had a suspicion my brother had tampered with documents
一個案子的文件
in a case I was working on.
他為什么要這么做
And why would he do that?
聽起來不怎么像兄弟所為
Doesn't sound particularly brotherly.
我認為他希望篡改的文件
I believe it was his hope that the tainted documents
會讓客戶打消讓我為其辯護的念頭
would cause the client to become disillusioned with my representation
而聘用他們之前的律師  韋克斯勒小姐
and return to their previous attorney, Ms. Wexler. ‭
這里我要說明一下  他們如愿以償了
Which, I should note, is precisely what happened.
反對
Objection.
我不是說韋克斯勒小姐對吉米的行為知情
I'm not saying Ms. Wexler knew what Jimmy was doing
或是參與其中
or had any involvement.
我只是指出結果的確如此
I'm only stating that it happened.
關于你對詹姆斯的懷疑
Did you have any evidence
你有證據證明嗎
to support your suspicions about James?
沒有  我的弟弟
No. My brother,
拋開別的不講  聰明過人
whatever else can be said of him, can be quite clever.
將自己的行徑掩蓋得非常好
Did an excellent job of covering his tracks.
反對
Objection.
證人剛承認了沒有相關證據
The witness has admitted there's no corroborating evidence
證明當事人犯下如上罪行
this supposed crime even occurred.
我想聽聽他要說什么
I'd like to hear what he has to say.
請繼續
We're going to continue.
你也可以進行盤問  韋克斯勒女士
Uh, we'll extend you the same latitude on cross, Ms. Wexler.
繼續  麥吉爾先生
Go on, Mr. McGill.
由于沒有確鑿證據
Without physical evidence,
我覺得能錄下他承認罪行
I felt that ‭a recorded confession --
如果我能錄到的話  是最好的機會
if I could get one -- was my best bet.
就本身而言  我知道這盤磁帶會沒有那么周密
On its own, I knew the tape would be somewhat flimsy,
但是個開始
but it was a start.
為更為縝密的立案打下基礎
A foundation for a more ironclad case.
我猜吉米肯定覺得
I suppose that Jimmy must have felt
那盤磁帶本身是一個有力的證據
the tape was decisive evidence on its own.
不然的話  他也不會闖進我家將它毀壞
Otherwise, he wouldn't have broken in to destroy it.
反對  還是任意猜測
Objection. More speculation.
他怎么能知道吉米腦中的想法
How can he know what was going on in Jimmy's head?
反對有效  我們只需要了解事情經過
Sustained. We just need to hear what happened,
麥吉爾先生
Mr. McGill.
很抱歉
I-I apologize.
我給我弟弟錄了音  對他進行立案
I recorded my brother to build a case against him.
在那時
And at the time,
可以說你的神志是完全清醒的嗎
would you say that you were in possession of your faculties?
恕我冒昧
All due respect, but --
但你在錄音中聽起來有一點神經錯亂
but you do sound somewhat unhinged on the recording.
是的  我能理解
Yes, I understand that.
但你所聽到的是戲劇
But what you heard was theater.
一場表演  是我假扮的
A performance, play-acting.
我夸張了我所患疾病的病征
I exaggerated the symptoms of my disease
以獲取事實真相
to extract the truth.
我們能談論一下你的疾病嗎
Can we talk about your disease for a moment?
我希望在場各位都能對其達成共識
I'd like everybody here to be on the same page about it.
當然可以
Of course.
有人稱之為EHS
It is sometimes referred to as EHS,
電磁過敏癥
electromagnetic hypersensitivity.
我稱之為對電磁的急性過敏
I describe it as an acute allergy to electromagnetism.
這并不是一個常見的病癥  對嗎
It's not a common condition, is it?
我知道這聽起來很奇怪  確實如此
I know it sounds strange. I do.
但三十年前  沒有人聽說過花生過敏
But 30 years ago, no one had heard of peanut allergies.
但你承認沒有人
But you admit that no one --
沒有醫生對你做出過診斷
no doctor -- has ever diagnosed you.
艾滋病直到1981年才被確診
AIDS was not identified properly until 1981.
直到83年才知道艾滋病是由艾滋病病毒引起
HIV wasn't known as the cause until '83.
這些事情需要時間來解釋  對醫生也是如此
These things take time to unravel, even for doctors.
你覺得你的病情
Would you say that your illness
會影響你清晰地思考嗎
affects your ability to think clearly?
不會  只會對我的生理造成影響
No. ‭It affects me physically.
會導致我產生劇烈的疼痛
It causes me great pain.
但我還是完全清醒的
However, I'm perfectly lucid.
謝謝
Thank you.
麥吉爾先生  我還有最后一個問題要問你
Mr. McGill, I have ‭only one more question for you.
你恨你的弟弟嗎
Do you hate your brother?
一點兒也不恨
Absolutely not.
我愛我的弟弟
I love my brother.
吉米本性并不壞
There's nothing malicious in Jimmy.
他總喜歡出于所謂高尚的理由
He has a way of doing the worst things
去做那些惡劣的事情
for reasons ‭that sound almost noble.
但我心中深知
But what I know for sure is that the law
法律神圣不可褻瀆
is too important to be toyed with.
這是人類最偉大的成就
It's mankind's greatest achievement
法治
the Rule of Law,
法治的意義就在于  不管你是誰
the idea that, no matter who you are,
你的行為都會產生后果
your actions have consequences.
而我弟弟對待法律的方式
And the way my brother treats the law --
讓我心碎不已
it breaks my heart.
所以我要這么做
That's why I did what I did.
不是為了傷害他  而是保護我所尊重的東西
Not to hurt him, but to protect something that I hold sacred.
謝謝  麥吉爾先生
Thank you, Mr. McGill.
州律師協會盤問完畢
The State Bar rests.
我覺得我們需要暫停一下
I think we need to put on the brakes.
抱歉  我和我的合伙律師需要時間商討
I'm sorry. My co-counsel and I need a moment to confer.
請盡快  律師
Please be brief, counselor.
好的
Yes, of course.
她會來
She'll be here.
你有想盤問他的嗎
Do you have anything for cross?
我能看一下你的筆記嗎
Can I look at your notes?
當然可以
Yeah, of course.
我們能...
Can we, um...
好的
Yeah.
很高興你能來
So glad you made it.
主席先生  不好意思
Mr. Chairman, I'm sorry.
我能去透口氣嗎
might I have a moment, to get a breath?
當然  麥吉爾先生
Oh, of course, Mr. McGill.
大伙  我們休庭十五分鐘
Uh, folks, let's call this 15.
大家  請準時回庭繼續聽審
Everybody, please be back and ready to go on the hour.
-麗貝卡  -查克
- Rebecca. - Chuck.
很高興見到你
It's good to see you.
不得不說  我有點兒意外
I have to say, I'm a bit surprised.
吉米傳訊你了嗎
Did Jimmy subpoena you?
你不在證人名單上  你不必作證
You're not on the witness list. You don't have to testify.
不不不  我不是來作證的
No, no, no, no. I'm not here for that.
那是來干什么的
Well, what, then?
查克  多希望你能告訴我
Chuck, I wish you'd told me.
我不敢相信你經歷了什么
I-I can't believe what you've been going through.
有多久了
How long has it been?
你是來幫我的
You're here to help.
因為這一切對我來說壓力太大了
Because all this is so stressful for me.
吉米是這么跟你說的嗎
Is that what Jimmy told you?
他很擔心你  查克
He's worried about you, Chuck.
盡管你們之間發生了這么多事
In spite of everything that's happened between the two of you,
他  他還是關心你的
he -- he cares.
他究竟說了什么
What exactly did he say?
他說你病了
Um, well, that you had been sick.
對電磁過敏
Allergic to electricity?
他給我看了你家的照片
He sent me pictures of the house.
查克  天啊
Chuck, my God. ‭
你為什么沒有告訴我
Why didn't you tell me?
我不想讓你心煩
I didn't want to upset you.
讓你產生顧慮
Worry you unnecessarily.
但既然你來了
But now you're here.
你現在也知道了
And now you know.
我來是因為我覺得應該這么做
I came because I thought it was the right thing.
我以為  你希望我來
I thought -- I don't know -- that you'd want me to.
但我想我只會讓你分心
But I guess that I'm more of a distraction.
所以...
So, uh... ‭
我會在城里待上幾天
I'm gonna be in town for a few days,
我很想和你聚聚
and I would love ‭to spend some time with you.
但現在  我還是先走吧
But right now, I-I think I should go.
不不  拜托  我希望你留下來
No. No, no, please. I want you to stay.
真的嗎  你見到我好像不太開心
Really? ‭You don't seem happy to see me.
我很開心
I am.
只是有些意外  僅此而已
Just surprised, that's all.
請你留下來
Please, stay.
你確定嗎
Are you sure?
我確定
Yes, I'm sure.
你聽信了很多讒言  麗貝卡
You've been sold a bill of goods, Rebecca.
我希望你親眼看到事實的真相
I want you to see what's what.
她和我想象的不一樣
She's not what I expected.
是嗎  你本來以為她什么樣
Oh, yeah? What'd you expect?
我不知道  只是...
I don't know. Just...
不是這樣
not her.
這事完了后  她會恨你的
You know, she's gonna hate you when this is over.
是啊
Yep.
好了  麥吉爾先生
All right, uh, Mr. McGill,
我提醒一下  你要遵從誓言
I'll remind you ‭you're still under oath.
我明白
I understand.
這次
At this time,
我想由我的合伙律師對證人進行盤問
I'd like to turn cross-examination over to my co-counsel,
詹姆斯·麥吉爾
James McGill.
這段期間發生了很多爭論
Uh, well, there's been a lot of fuss about it,
但你我從未談過你錄制的這盤錄音帶
but you and I have never really talked about this tape you made.
你闖入我家毀壞帶子后  我們就沒機會談了
We lost the opportunity when you burglarized my house to destroy it.
有道理
Fair enough.
那件事是我不對
Um, and I was in the wrong there.
但我還是想聽聽你錄制那盤帶子的
But, still, I'd like to try and follow your story
原因和方法
of why and how you recorded it.
你想說帶子是偽造的嗎
Is this where you claim the tape is spurious?
其實不是你的聲音嗎
That it's not really your voice?
不  那是我的聲音
No. That's me on the tape.
但我仍然有些疑問
But, still, I have some questions.
比如那臺錄音機
Like, the recorder,
你碰到它一定非常疼吧
it must've hurt like hell for you to touch that.
的確有一定程度上的不舒服
There was a degree ‭of discomfort, that's true.
你當時把錄音機藏在哪兒
And where did you hide it?
錄到的聲音很清晰
I mean, the sound's pretty clear,
所以應該不是藏在沙發墊子里吧
so it wasn't in ‭the couch cushions, was it?
壓在太空毯底下  看不見
Tucked under a space blanket. Out of sight.
所以我肯定不會發現
So there's no chance I would see it.
以你家當時的情況來說
Not with the state your place was in.
-對嗎  -我想是吧
- Isn't that right? ‭- I suppose.
你能否向紀律委員會描述當時的情況
Would you like to set the scene for the Disciplinary Committee?
告訴他們  錄音時
Tell them, you know, what your house looked like
你房子是什么樣
at the time of the recording.
反對  與本案有關嗎
Objection. Relevance?
錄音時的環境與本案有極大關系
Well, the circumstances of the recording are materially relevant.
如果不知道錄音時發生的事
How can you know what the tape really means
又怎能知道帶子的真正意義呢
unless you know what was going on when it was recorded?
反對無效  證人請回答問題
Overruled. The witness can answer the question.
我用錫箔  麻布和牛皮紙做的絕緣層蓋住大部分墻
I covered most of the walls with Foil-Scrim-Kraft insulation.
我還掛上了一些太空毯
I also hung a number of space blankets.
是密實的聚酯薄膜
Compact Mylar sheets.
它們可以幫我隔離
They insulate and protect
輕度電磁輻射
against mild ‭electromagnetic radiation.
所以墻上和天花板上
All right, so, shiny insulation
掛滿了閃亮的隔離層和太空毯
and space blankets all over the walls and the ceiling.
好像在舞廳的發光球燈里一樣
It was like being inside of a disco ball.
你到底想說什么
Do you have a point?
我是驚嘆
Well, I'm impressed
你為了讓我落入陷阱  做了那么多工作
by how much work went into entrapping me.
你真是竭盡全力啊
You went all out.
我沒有設陷阱
I didn't entrap you.
我只是刺激你承認了而已
I provoked an admission in adverse interest.
那不是一回事
That's not the same thing.
你怎么知道能成功
How did you know it would work?
什么意思
What do you mean?
你怎么知道你"刺激"我能成功
How did you know your "provocation" would work?
你為什么覺得一些發光的塑料
Why'd you think a bunch of shiny plastic
能讓我開口
would make me say anything?
難道不是因為你知道
Isn't it because you knew that it was precisely the thing
那種東西最讓我擔心
that would worry me so much
為了駁倒你  我什么話都說得出來
that I'd say anything to talk you down?
反對
Objection.
好的  撤回
Okay. Withdrawn.
我們繼續說你的房子
Let's -- Let's get back to your house,
所有表面都用錫箔紙蓋起來了
every surface covered in tinfoil.
那可一點都不瘋癲  是吧
Nothing crazy about that, huh?
如我所說  我把病情夸大了
As I've said, ‭I was playing up my condition.
通常  我的房子完全正常
Usually, it's ‭a perfectly normal house.
你認為你的房子很正常嗎
You think your house is normal?
我能請您看看九號證物嗎
Can I call your attention to Exhibit Nine?
這是你家  對嗎
This is your house, right?
是的
Yes.
電線外露
So, exposed wires.
有個便攜爐
There's a camp stove.
報紙上放著一盞煤油燈
There's a lantern on top of newspapers.
這算正常嗎
You call this normal?
我稱之為適應
I call them adaptations.
針對身體疾病做出的預防措施
A prophylactic measure for a physical, medical condition.
授予我對你的監護權的那位醫生
Did the doctor who granted me Guardianship
認為這是身體疾病嗎
for you think this was a physical condition?
反對
Objection.
不能將其作為證據
You can't introduce a TEG as evidence.
而且  陪審團已經裁決
Besides which, the panel has already ruled
麥吉爾先生的心理健康不在討論范疇
that Mr. McGill's mental health is not at issue.
不  州律師協會直接通過裁決
No, the State Bar opened the door to this on direct
是因為證人當時談及他"夸大"了的病情
when the witness talked about his supposed "play-acting."
所以讓我繼續提問很合理
Allowing me to follow up on cross is only reasonable.
我們當時討論的是身體過敏病癥
We discussed the physical allergy,
而不是精神疾病
not a mental disability.
說法不同而已
Potato, po-tah-to.
歸根結底
It comes down to this --
想理解我當時的想法
In order to understand what I was thinking,
你就要從我的視角看查克
you need to see Chuck through my eyes.
你得知道我當時是否覺得那盤帶子是證據
You need to know if I believed that tape was evidence.
而我認為這盤帶子只證明了一件事
And I say it was evidence of only one thing --
我哥哥恨我
My brother hates me.
他聲稱他欺騙我  是為了讓我說出真相
Now, he claims that he lied to me to get me to tell the truth.
我告訴您
And I'm telling you
我欺騙我哥哥  是為了讓他好過一些
I lied to my brother to make him feel better.
您相信誰的話
Which of us you believe
取決于我們如何理解查爾斯·麥吉爾的思維方式
depends on how we all understand the mind of Charles McGill.
我們確實答應給辯方一些自由度
Well, we did promise the defense some leeway.
你可以繼續說
You may proceed.
-謝謝  主席先生  -但你注意點
- Thank you, Mr. Chairman. - But watch yourself.
查克  我想談談更久之前的事
Chuck, I'd like to go back a little further,
這些癥狀剛出現那時
talk about when these symptoms first started.
是在你剛離婚后不久  對嗎
It was shortly after you were divorced, is that right?
是的
Yes.
你覺得離婚的壓力是你的病因嗎
You think the stress of the divorce brought on the illness?
應該不是  我們當時是和平分手
I doubt it. ‭It was an amicable split.
我前妻和我仍然相處愉快
My ex-wife and I are still on good terms.
事實上  你前妻今天也在現場  對嗎
In fact, your ex-wife is present with us today, is she not?
你們上一次見面是什么時候
When was the last time you two saw each other?
反對  這里不是家事法庭
Objection. This is not family court.
我們在此不是為證人的離婚重新提起訴訟
We're not here to re-litigate the witness' divorce.
我不懂問這些有什么意義
I can't see what purpose this serves.
我懂
I can.
讓我來告訴你  我弟弟為什么
I'll tell you why my brother
邀我前妻出席這場聽證會
brought my ex-wife to this hearing.
她因為關心我  跨越六千四百公里來到這里
4,000 miles she came, lured by concern for me.
吉米想提出的是  我上次見她時
What Jimmy's driving at is the last time I saw her,
隱瞞了我的病情
I covered up my illness.
當時我已經受病情折磨了一段時間
I'd been suffering from it for some time,
但我想盡辦法對她隱瞞了事實
but I went to great lengths to conceal that fact from her.
很抱歉我欺騙了你  麗貝卡
I'm sorry I deceived you, Rebecca.
我不希望你看輕我
I didn't want you to think less of me.
現在吉米當著你的面  揭穿我的秘密
Now Jimmy has outed me in front of you.
你知道為什么嗎
You know why?
想亂我陣腳
To rattle me.
他知道我仍然對...
He knows I still have a...
我的前妻還存有深厚感情
lot of, feeling for my ex-wife.
他想以此擊垮我
He's hoping ‭this will break me down.
在我的傷口上撒鹽
Split me apart at the seams,
就像《梅森探案集》里兇手供認那樣
like a murderer confessing on an episode of "Perry Mason."
抱歉讓你失望了  吉米
Well, I'm sorry ‭to disappoint you, Jimmy.
我的回答是否使你滿意呢
Have I answered your questions to your satisfaction?
還有其他問題嗎
Do you have anything else?
是的  我有
Yeah, I do.
之前  你說還有其他疾病
Earlier, you talked about other diseases.
像你說的身體疾病
Physical conditions, you said.
那么  如果你當時患有...
So, okay, if you'd had, um -- I don't know --
肺癌  你會告訴麗貝卡嗎
lung cancer, would you have told Rebecca then?
真是那樣的話  也許吧
If that had been the case, maybe.
我也許會那么做
I might have.
有什么不同嗎
So how is this different?
麥吉爾先生  請跳過
Mr. McGill. Move it along.
你不用回答這個問題
You don't have to answer that.
我想談論實質性問題
I want to get down to brass tacks.
我想聽非常詳細的細節
I want to be very, very specific here.
得這種病  是什么感覺
This illness, what does it feel like?
你說過它令人很痛苦
You mentioned it's painful.
沒錯
It is.
它使我胸悶氣急  呼吸困難
There's a tightness in my chest, difficulty breathing,
令我感受到萬箭穿心的痛苦
and pain, burning pain.
這種痛苦吞噬了我
The pain spreads everywhere.
聽上去很可怕  現在還痛嗎
Sounds horrible. Does it hurt right now?
沒錯  還是會讓我感到不適
There's always some discomfort, yes.
現代社會離不開電力的使用
Electricity is everywhere in the modern world.
但我很感謝今天陪審會給予我的
But I very much appreciate the indulgence of the panel
理解和通融
for their accommodation here today.
我可以克服
I can handle this fine.
所以關了燈  你就感覺不到了
Right, so, with the lights out, you don't feel them?
如果沒有電流  就感覺不到
If the current's not flowing, no.
抱歉沒關安全出口燈
Oh. Sorry about the exit signs.
我想他們不能替你關掉
I guess they couldn't kill those for you.
它沒有接通太多電流  并且離我很遠
Well, they're not drawing much current, and they're far away.
按平方反比定律來說
Intensity drops off with distance,
強度會隨著距離增加而縮減
per the inverse-square law.
行  很強
Okay, whoa!
平方反比...  我不是物理學家
Inverse-square -- I'm not a physicist.
你能不用那么學術的詞語嗎
Could you dumb that down a shade for me?
距離越遠
The farther away it is,
就需要越強大的來源來產生效應
the stronger the source needs to be to have an effect.
明白了  懂了
Got it. Got it.
如果我有一塊小電池  比如手表的那種
So, if I had a small battery, say, from a watch or something,
然后拿著它靠近你  碰到你的皮膚
and I got it close to you, close to your skin,
你會有感覺嗎
you'd know?
是的  我會感覺到
I would feel it, yes.
你現在能察覺到
Can you feel more current
從其他方向傳來的電流嗎
coming from any particular direction right now?
比如那堵墻后面
Uh, from that back wall
或者那邊
or, uh, from over there
或者從地板上
or up through the floor?
你能告訴我們現在離你最近的電源在哪嗎
Can you tell us where the nearest source is right now?
吉米  你口袋里是不是有什么東西
Jimmy, do you have something in your pocket?
是的  實際上我有
Yes, I do, as a matter of fact.
是我的手機
My cellphone.
你應該能從這個距離察覺到
From this distance, you should feel it,
但你沒有  是吧
and you don't, do you?
麥吉爾先生  你應該把電子設備放在外面
Mr. McGill, you were warned to leave your electronics outside.
沒關系
It's all right.
我可以看看嗎
May I?
正如我所想的那樣  這里面沒裝電池
Just as I thought. ‭There's no battery in here.
你把電池拆下來了
You removed the battery.
真是個遺憾的小把戲  是吧
That's a sorry little trick, isn't it?
是的  被你當場發現了  查克
Yeah, you got me, Chuck. Dead to rights.
我卸掉了電池
I removed the battery.
-反對  -反對有效
- Objection. - Sustained.
你已經問的差不多了  麥吉爾先生
Y-You've taken all the leeway you're getting, Mr. McGill.
趕緊收尾
Wrap it up fast.
天  吉米
God, Jimmy.
你現在還不相信這是真的嗎
Don't you know by now this is real?
我能感覺電流
I feel this.
這是對外部刺激的物理反應
It's a physical response to stimuli.
這不是什么怪癖
It's not a quirk.
我到底要怎么做才能向你證明
What do I have to do to prove it to you?
我不知道  查克
I don't know, Chuck.
你能伸進你胸前的口袋
Could you reach into your breast pocket
告訴我里面有什么嗎
and tell me what's there?
又是什么把戲
What now?
你能告訴法官那是什么嗎
Can you tell the court what that was?
-一塊電池 -董事長先生...
- A battery. - Mr. Chairman --
-拜托  -你認識后面那位先生嗎
- Please. - Do you recognize that man in back?
他叫休·巴布諾  他是我的證人
His name is Huell Babineaux. He's on our witness list.
你在樓梯上撞到了他
You bumped into him in the stairway.
他作證在一個半小時前放了這塊滿電量的
He'll testify he planted this fully charged battery on you
電池在你身上
over an hour and a half ago.
一小時四十三分鐘
Hour and 43 minutes ago.
一小時四十三分鐘  謝謝  巴布諾先生
An hour and 43 minutes. Thank you, Mr. Babineaux.
而你卻毫無察覺
And you felt nothing.
不不不
No, no, no. No, no.
這是個把戲  它必須...
It's a trick. It has to --
適可而止吧
Enough is enough.
我認為麥吉爾先生的精神疾病不是問題
I submit that Mr. McGill's mental illness is a non-issue.
-即使他有精神分裂  -精神分...
- If he were schizophrenic... - Schizo--
也不能抹滅被告之前所...
...it wouldn't take away from the fact that the defendant
我不是瘋子
I am not crazy!
I am not crazy.
我知道他調換了號碼
I know he swapped those numbers.
我知道是1216號
I knew it was 1216.
和《大憲章》簽署日一數之差
One after Magna Carta.
我怎么可能犯這種錯誤
As if I could ever make such a mistake.
絕對不會
Never. Never!
我就是...  就是沒辦法證明
I just -- I just couldn't prove it.
他掩蓋了自己的行蹤
H-H-He covered his tracks.
他還讓復印店的傻蛋幫他撒謊
He got that idiot at the copy shop to lie for him.
麥吉爾先生  你不用...
Mr. McGill, please. You don't have to go in--
你們覺得這很大不了嗎
You think this is something?
你們覺得這種欺詐很惡劣嗎
You think this is bad, this -- this chicanery?
他還干過更壞的事  那個廣告牌
He's done worse. That billboard!
你是說那個男的就那么恰好掉下去了
Are you telling me that a man just happens to fall like that?
不  他一手策劃的
No. He orchestrated it!
吉米
Jimmy!
他對著天窗拉了泡屎
He defecated through a sunroof!
是我拯救了他  但我后悔了
And I saved him, and I shouldn't have.
我把他帶進了自己的律所
I took him into my own firm.
我當時想什么呢
What was I thinking?!
他就是不肯改變
He'll never change.
死不悔改
從他九歲開始  他就一直這副德行
Ever since he was 9, always the same.
管不住自己去動收銀柜的手
Couldn't keep his hands out of the cash drawer.
但咱吉米不是這種人
But not our Jimmy.
不可能是咱寶貴的吉米啊
Couldn't be precious Jimmy!
他就是偷竊成癮
Stealing them blind.
而這種人卻當了一名律師
And he gets to be a lawyer?!
真是見了鬼
What a sick joke!
當年有機會的時候我就該阻攔他
I should have stopped him when I had the chance!
你們得阻攔他
And you -- you have to stop him!
你們...
You --
我道歉
I apologize.
我沒能穩定自己的情緒
I lost my train of thought.
失去了理智
I got carried away.
還有其他問題嗎
Do you have anything else?
沒  我問完了
No. Nothing further.
安全出口